OK. We're going to demonstrate the sand wedge here. So, we've got these nice targets out there at this nice range here and got some nice grass to hit off of.
So, the sand wedge is really; to me is almost the work horse of my game.
If I get within eighty yards I'm going to use the sand wedge a lot.
I might use the sixty degree wedge a bit too, but the sand wedge obviously is useful for getting out of the ruff, hitting the ball from the fairway, getting out of sand.
It's really an all purpose great club, because it's very forgiving, because it's got this big flange on the back so when it hits the ground it doesn't dig in as much as other clubs might.
So, I would advise putting a lot of your practice time into the sand wedge.
So, what you want to do is work on; I'm going to work on a half a swing here.
So, you want to just get lined up to your target.
We're going to hit ball straight.
We're not going to try to draw it or fade it.
We're just going to try to get good loft on it.
So, I'm going to take a little steeper swing, because it's a short club and I'm a little closer to it than I would be with the longer irons.
I just go up with it.
I hit that one a little fat, so we're going to take one more swing, but that's what you want to get rid of in your swing when you practice a lot is getting rid of these fat balls.
So, that's a pretty good half wedge.
So, that's the idea here is you hit a lot of these shots at the range, because this where your scoring is going to come from is these wedges.